Next, let's talk about the four basic steps to first aid care.
Step one is scene safety.
Your very first priority is your own safety and the patient's.
Scan the area for environmental hazards like fire, traffic, or water.
If the scene is unsafe, do not approach, just call for professional help and wait for them
to arrive.
Remember, you can't help if you're hurt.
This is also a good time to put on any personal protective equipment if available.
If you must move the person, either to perform CPR or get them to safety, do it quickly.
If you suspect a neck or spinal injury and have a second person to help, try to protect
their head and neck while you move them.
Step two is to identify the emergency.
Remember, people won't always be able to tell you that something is wrong.
Check their responsiveness and breathing and observe them for any sudden changes in their
appearance or behavior.
If the person is responsive, introduce yourself and ask if you can help.
If they are unresponsive, we assume consent, meaning we act as if they want our help.
Step three is to call 9-1-1 and get an AED.
If there are others around, tell someone specifically to call 9-1-1 and have them find an AED.
If you are alone, call 9-1-1 and place them on speakerphone.
Step four is to provide care.
You are essentially the caretaker until professional help takes over the scene.
In the next few slides, we're going to walk through exactly what that care looks like
for different injuries and emergencies.